<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Konstantin Mishchenko on Konstantin Mishchenko</title>
    <link>https://konstmish.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Konstantin Mishchenko on Konstantin Mishchenko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Konstantin Mishchenko</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic Distributed Learning with Gradient Quantization and Variance Reduction</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/publication/quant_vr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/publication/quant_vr/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am a member of the program committee for NeurIPS and UAI 2019</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/post/19_neurips_uai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/post/19_neurips_uai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a successful round of reviews for International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) I was invited to serve on committee for two more important ML conferences: Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) and Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI). The review period for UAI is from 21 March to 21 April 2019 and all paper submissions have already been done, while for NeurIPS the deadline to submit a paper is on 23 May 2019 and the review period is from 18 June to 15 July 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m visiting Martin Jaggi from 18 February to 15 March</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/post/18_epfl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/post/18_epfl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is no specific project to work on yet, but my research interests are almost a subset of what Martin and his group have worked on. I would not be surprised if it leads to more than one project and hope that this visit will not be the last one :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of today, the group&amp;rsquo;s website is available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://mlo.epfl.ch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://mlo.epfl.ch/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our group photo</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/post/18_group/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/post/18_group/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; /&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>99% of Parallel Optimization is Inevitably a Waste of Time</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/publication/99/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/publication/99/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Learning with Compressed Gradient Differences</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/publication/diana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/publication/diana/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Stochastic Penalty Model for Convex and Nonconvex Optimization with Big Constraints</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/publication/penalty/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/publication/penalty/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am a program committee member for ICML 2019!</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/post/icml-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/post/icml-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first time being a reviewer for such a venue, so I hope I will not be &amp;ldquo;that stupid reviewer&amp;rdquo; :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prize winner at IEEEXtreme</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/post/ieeextreme-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/post/ieeextreme-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a 24 hours programming competition Alibek and I were solving tough mathematical and programming problems for the sake of fun and, &lt;em&gt;maybe&lt;/em&gt;, some prizes. Fortunately, we managed to make it to top 100, which means that we are eligible for prizes from IEEE!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year I participated in the same competition with Samuel Horvath, but back then we were only 123rd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link to the results: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeextreme.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IEEEXtreme-12.0-Global-Ranking.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://ieeextreme.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IEEEXtreme-12.0-Global-Ranking.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SEGA: Variance Reduction via Gradient Sketching</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/publication/sega/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/publication/sega/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A NIPS paper got accepted!</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/post/nips-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/post/nips-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy to say that our paper &amp;ldquo;SEGA: Variance Reduction via Gradient Sketching&amp;rdquo; about variance reduction for coordinate descent methods was accepted to NIPS. In this work, we discover how coordinate descent methods can be extended to problems with non-separable regularizer. We consider minibatch, importance sampling and acceleration of the produced method. What&amp;rsquo;s more, we additionally introduced a variant with non-trivial sketches of the gradient, under maximal possible stepsizes can be larger by an arbitrary number than in classical coordinate descent methods.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Distributed Flexible Delay-tolerant Proximal Gradient Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/publication/dave_siopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/publication/dave_siopt/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m interning at Amazon August-November</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/post/amazon-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/post/amazon-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my MSc in Paris, we had an amazing course taught by Fabian Pedregosa (&lt;a href=&#34;http://fa.bianp.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fa.bianp.net/&lt;/a&gt;) and Fajwel Fogel (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.di.ens.fr/~fogel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.di.ens.fr/~fogel/&lt;/a&gt;). In this course, we learnt how to use Python for data analysis and to evaluate our knowledge we needed to participate in a challenge with other Paris students. Together with Matthieu Mazzolini and Paul Dufosse (they are very cool guys) I chose PlumeLabs challenge where the data was the air pollution in different cities over time. Long story short, we won it, which is totally due to my teammates, I would never be able to do it alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back then, both Fabian and Fajwel were supervised by Alexandre d&amp;rsquo;Aspremont (postdoc and PhD student respectively). And they invited another postdoc of Alexandre, Federico Vaggi, to help them with grading our final presentations. Based on our grade, I guess that we made good impression on them, and I was pretty happy about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is interesting is that Federico just a few weeks later was already working at Amazon. Last Fall I wrote Federico an email and after a few interviews a got accepted to intern in the same research team.
The topic of my internship is not specified yet, but it will involve research in machine learning for problems motivated by Amazon&amp;rsquo;s needs. The coolest thing is that while the team&amp;rsquo;s work is very applied, for my internship they agree to work on quite theoretical topics, so that I would be able to use it for my PhD. Let us see what results I will have by the end of my internship.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After the first hackathon at the Vatican</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/post/vatican-2018mar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/post/vatican-2018mar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To begin with, the pope didn&amp;rsquo;t come to us to say &amp;ldquo;hi&amp;rdquo;. He gave a speech from a balcony instead and it was the first time he said &amp;ldquo;hackathon&amp;rdquo; in public. Moreover, it would be unfair to say that we were not welcome: the Vatican invested deeply in this event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://konstmish.github.io/img/vatican_priest.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;priest&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hackathon went well, although our team didn&amp;rsquo;t win anything. It was a nice experience and since I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to win a hackathon at the first attempt, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty happy about having being there. And as we actually did work a lot on our project, after coming back to KAUST I had an amazing 12-hours sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://konstmish.github.io/img/major_league_hacking.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;coding&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was really surprising is the dinner that we had in a private palace. This palace is called &amp;ldquo;Palazzo Taverna&amp;rdquo; and was built by Cardinal Giordano Orsini approximately in 1400. There is a short wikipedia page in Italian about it: &lt;a href=&#34;https://it.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palazzo_Taverna_(Roma)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;. Every room looks so fancy, there are so many paintings everywhere, it looks overwhelmingly luxurious. I bet everyone was impressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://konstmish.github.io/img/vatican_paintings.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;vatican_paintings&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://konstmish.github.io/img/vatican_dinner.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;vatican_dinner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VHacks – A hackathon at the Vatican</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/post/vatican-2018jan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/post/vatican-2018jan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was selected to be one of 120 students invited to the Vatican to participate in a hackathon. Hackathon&amp;rsquo;s theme are (1) social inclusion, (2) interfaith dialogue and (3) migrants &amp;amp; refugees. I am no expert in religions or migrants problems, so I applied and got accepted to participate addressing the first theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The even is organized by OPTIC - &amp;ldquo;an organization founded in 2012 dedicated to research and innovation regarding the ethics of new and disruptive technologies&amp;rdquo;. More details can be found on this webpage:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://vhacks.org/faq/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://vhacks.org/faq/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have a good hackathon participations record, but I believe it will be amazing :) It is especially nice to represent KAUST in such an event.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
