<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Konstantin Mishchenko</title>
    <link>https://konstmish.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Konstantin Mishchenko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Konstantin Mishchenko</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://konstmish.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I am a program committee member for ICML 2019!</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/post/icml-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/post/icml-2019/</guid>
      <description>This is my first time being a reviewer for such a venue, so I hope I will not be &amp;ldquo;that stupid reviewer&amp;rdquo; :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prize winner at IEEEXtreme</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/post/ieeextreme-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/post/ieeextreme-2018/</guid>
      <description>In a 24 hours programming competition Alibek and I were solving tough mathematical and programming problems for the sake of fun and, maybe, some prizes. Fortunately, we managed to make it to top 100, which means that we are eligible for prizes from IEEE!
Last year I participated in the same competition with Samuel Horvath, but back then we were only 123rd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A NIPS paper got accepted!</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/post/nips-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/post/nips-2018/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m happy to say that our paper &amp;ldquo;SEGA: Variance Reduction via Gradient Sketching&amp;rdquo; about variance reduction for coordinate descent methods was accepted to NIPS. In this work, we discover how coordinate descent methods can be extended to problems with non-separable regularizer. We consider minibatch, importance sampling and acceleration of the produced method. What&amp;rsquo;s more, we additionally introduced a variant with non-trivial sketches of the gradient, under maximal possible stepsizes can be larger by an arbitrary number than in classical coordinate descent methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m interning at Amazon this summer</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/post/amazon-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/post/amazon-2018/</guid>
      <description>Update: due to a visa delay my internship got postponed.
During my MSc in Paris, we had an amazing course taught by Fabian Pedregosa (http://fa.bianp.net/) and Fajwel Fogel (http://www.di.ens.fr/~fogel/). In this course, we learnt how to use Python for data analysis and to evaluate our knowledge we needed to participate in a challenge with other Paris students. Together with Matthieu Mazzolini and Paul Dufosse (they are very cool guys) I chose PlumeLabs challenge where the data was the air pollution in different cities over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After the first hackathon at the Vatican</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/post/vatican-2018mar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/post/vatican-2018mar/</guid>
      <description>To begin with, the pope didn&amp;rsquo;t come to us to say &amp;ldquo;hi&amp;rdquo;. He gave a speech from a balcony instead and it was the first time he said &amp;ldquo;hackathon&amp;rdquo; in public. Moreover, it would be unfair to say that we were not welcome: the Vatican invested deeply in this event.
The hackathon went well, although our team didn&amp;rsquo;t win anything. It was a nice experience and since I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to win a hackathon at the first attempt, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty happy about having being there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VHacks – A hackathon at the Vatican</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/post/vatican-2018jan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/post/vatican-2018jan/</guid>
      <description>I was selected to be one of 120 students invited to the Vatican to participate in a hackathon. Hackathon&amp;rsquo;s theme are (1) social inclusion, (2) interfaith dialogue and (3) migrants &amp;amp; refugees. I am no expert in religions or migrants problems, so I applied and got accepted to participate addressing the first theme.
The even is organized by OPTIC - &amp;ldquo;an organization founded in 2012 dedicated to research and innovation regarding the ethics of new and disruptive technologies&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INFORMS Optimization Society Conference</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/post/informs-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/post/informs-2018/</guid>
      <description>In September Peter suggested me to take part in organizing a few sessions at INFORMS Optimization Society Conference. Since I had no idea of what it means back then, I decided to first try with just one. In addition, I could choose to invite either 3 or 4 speakers, and I decided to go for the former option. It allowed me to choose speakers carefully, but unfortunately I didn&amp;rsquo;t foresee that one of the speakers I invited may not be able to come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting Cambridge</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/post/visiting-cambridge-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/post/visiting-cambridge-2017/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m visiting Dr. Carola-Bibiane Schönlieb&amp;rsquo;s group at Cambridge until 9 January. I will also be here for a few more weeks in February.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IEEEXtreme</title>
      <link>https://konstmish.github.io/post/ieeextreme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstmish.github.io/post/ieeextreme/</guid>
      <description>I teamed up with Samuel Horvath to participate in a competition called &amp;ldquo;IEEEXtreme&amp;rdquo; organized by IEEE for students worldwide. We got ranked 123 worldwide or 43 in our Region (Africa, Europe and Middle East). Unfortunately, we didn&amp;rsquo;t get in top 100, so we are not going to get T-shirts as a prize, but the competition was extremely fun and it was cool to work with Samuel in a team.
Official results are available here: http://ieeextreme.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>